Guide to the Brian R. McNaught papers, circa 1970-2004
McNaught, Brian R. papers, circa 1970-2004
- Series VIII. Support Documents
  - Publications
    - Christopher Street, Sep. 1979; CCPA News and Views (Newsletter of Catholics for Christian Political Action), Nov. 1978; Probe, Mar. 1978, vol. VII no. 6; The Pilot, Nov. 1987, vol. 158, no. 43; "A New Day," Dec. 1980, vol. IV, no. 8; "Declaration on Certain Questions Concerning Sexual Ethics" Vatican City, 1975; "Catholic Coalition for Gay Civil Rights," n.d.; "Homosexuality and the Church of Today," National Catholic Reporter, Mar. 26, 1976; "A Model for Ministry to the Homosexual Community," Salvatorian Gay Ministry Task Force, Mar. 24, 1974, 1974-1987 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "The Report and Recommendations of the Commission on Homosexuality," Episcopal Diocese of Michigan, July 1973; The Other Side, June 1982; "Must We Choose Sides? Christian Commitment for the '80s" Sept. 1979, 1973-1982 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Newsweek, Aug. 8, 1983; Psychology Today, March 1981; Two of Me: The Struggle with Sin, Dave Wilkerson, 1980; "Artcetera," 1985, 1980-1985 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Caregiver's Manual- Caring for the Person with AIDS at home" n.d.; "Breaking the Silence, Overcoming the Fear: Homophobia Education" n.d.; Geo, vol. 2, Feb. 1980, 1980, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Coming Out- A Gay Guide to Notre Dame and South Bend," Fall 1977; "How can You Tell if You're Really in Love?" 1980; "A Proposal for the Prevention and Correction of Delinquency Among Youth," 1965; "The Myths of Homosexuality," Nov. 1973; "The Truth Seeker," July/Aug. 1989; Newsweek, June 6, 1977; The Witness, Feb. 1976; Oct. 1977; Oct. 1978; June 1979; Oct. 1979, 1965-1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - The Advocate, issue 559, Sept. 11, 1990; Training and Development, Jan. 1992; "Liberty and Justice for All: A Discussion Guide" Dec. 1974, 1974-1990 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Ladies Home Journal, Dec. 1980; "Planned Parenthood Resource Review," vol. 5, no. 1, 1986-87; Psychology Today, Jun. 1986; Ms., Dec. 1979; "Behind Closet Doors: The Door Looks at Homosexuality," The Wittenburg Door, no. 39 Oct/Nov. 1977, 1979-1987 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Analysis of the 96th Congress," The Gay Rights National Lobby, 1980; Spirituality Today, vol. 30, no. 2, June 1978; "Celebration '90 - Gay Games III and Cultural Festival" Official Program, Vancouver, Aug. 4-11, 1990; "Maklary's Digest," no. 2, Dec. 16, 1981 "Standing Commission on Human Affairs and Health," 1980, 1978-1990 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "How Can You Tell if you're Really in Love?" 1980; American Educator, Fall 1978; "One in 10: A profile of Alaska's Lesbian and Gay Community," 1986; press release re: Massachusetts Attorney General James M. Shannon's 1987 Executive Order prohibiting discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation, AIDS/HIV status (also related articles); Free Inquiry, vol. 1, no. 1 Winter 1980/81; "The AIDS Action Committee of Massachusetts: the Next Decade," 1992; "Ten Heavy Facts about Sex," 1971; "Help Yourself: a self-help handbook by and for the students of the University of Maryland," 1979; "Sex in a Plain Brown Wrapper: By the students, for the students," Syracuse University, 1976, 1971-1992 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "The Consequences of Being Gay: A Report on the Quality of Life for Lesbian, Gay and Bisexual Students at the University of Massachusetts at Amherst," June 1985l "Homosexuality: (Part I) What Science Understands, (Part II) Before Counseling Gays and Lesbians," 1987; "The Gay and Lesbian Speakers Bureau Manual," Jan. 1984, 1984-1987 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "How to be a Trainer: A Self-Instructional Manual for Training in Sexual and Reproductive Health Care," Planned Parenthood of Maryland, 1980; "Speaking for Ourselves: Training for the Gay and Lesbian Speakers Bureau of Boston," n.d., 1980, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Tommy's Connection, vol. 1, no. 18 n.d.; The Watchtower, Aug. 15, 1974; Marquette Tribune, April 25, 1975, April 30, 1975, May 5, 1975, Nov. 28- Dec. 1, 1989; Lifestyle Boston, Nov. 27, 1979; High Gear, Nov. 6, 1981; Gay News, Sept. 4-17, 1981; Gay Liberator, April- May 1975; Gay Liberator, Feb.- March 1975; Entertainment West, n.d.; Civil Liberties, Nov. 1977; Commonweal, May 24, 1974; Bondings, Fall 1985 and Sept. 29, 1978, Sept. 30, 1978, Oct. 17, 1978, June 12, 1979, Oct. 1, 1979, Oct. 2, 1979; The Michigan Catholic, vol. 108, no. 1 Jan. 4, 1980; A.D. (After Detroit) 1977; On the Edge: A Catholic Worker Newspaper, vol 3, no. 1, Jan. 20, 1978; Commitment, Jan. 1979; The National Catholic Reporter, March 8, 1974 (vol. 10, no. 19), Nov. 14, 1975 (vol. 12, no. 4), June 18, 1976, Nov. 5, 1976 (vol. 13, no. 3), Oct. 21, 1977 (vol. 13, no. 46), Nov. 11, 1977 (vol. 14, no. 4), Nov. 18, 1977 (vol. 14, no. 5), Jan. 27, 1978 (vol. 14, no. 14), Feb. 10, 1978 (vol. 14, no. 16), March 3, 1978 (vol. 14, no. 19), March 10, 1978 (vol. 14, no. 20), May 19, 1978 (vol. 14, no. 30), June 2, 1978 (vol. 14, no. 32), June 16, 1978 (vol. 14, no. 33), Aug. 18, 1978, Oct. 13, 1978 (vol. 14, no. 42), Nov. 21, 1980 (vol. 17, no. 5); Southern Cross, May 29, 1975, 1974-1989 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings and Articles, 1970-1985 (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
    - Bryant, Anita Articles, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 2001-2002 (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Series IX. Visual Materials and Ephemera
  Included are various posters, and some advertisements for McNaught lectures. Also old calendars, buttons, two Boston Gay Pride hats; slides and photographs of McNaught from the 1970s. Included in this box is a film strip/tape presentation entitled "The Hidden Minority: Homosexuality in Our Society."
  - Photos of McNaught, 1975-1980 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Slides and Photos for video "On Being Gay", 1979 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Photos for Metro Gay News, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
  - Posters advertising McNaught Lectures; Calendars from 1979-1980; Records, Filmstrips and Tapes from "The Hidden Minority: Homosexuality in our Society" n.d.; Lesbian and Gay Pride Day - Boston hats 1983; Miscellaneous Buttons and Pins; Metropolitan Detroit Science Fair ribbon 1962; Cassette tape and Lyrics from Lynn Lavner n.d.; 15 boxes of slides of McNaught; Record cover "Jungle Drums - Wild Fantasy"; Miscellaneous Posters and Drawings; Book covers for On Being Gay (Box 22)
  - Drag Show Advertisements, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Workplace Photos, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - "Gays Make It In Massachussetts" T-Shirt, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - "Let's Be Frank" T-Shirt (Frank Barney), n.d. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - "Make Love, Not Breeder Babies" T-Shirt, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Nametag for XVII World Congress of Sexology (Box 23, Folder 80)
  - "Sex Camp" advertising postcards (Box 23, Folder 73)
- Series X. Audio and Video Materials
  This series contains videos and tapes made by McNaught to be used primarily as educational tools, as well as to help people struggling with their own sexual identity.
  - Audio Recordings
    - All God's Children - McNaught, tr6845a
    - Brian McNaught with Bruds - Jan. 20 1987, tr6846a
    - New Ways Ministry: Growing Up Gay and Catholic - McNaught, tr6847a
    - Brian McNaught on Homosexuality, tr6848a
    - Human Sexuality - Brian McNaught, Nov. 5 1980 - Part I, tr6849a
    - Human Sexuality - Brian McNaught, Nov. 5 1980 - Part II, tr6850a
    - Brian McNaught Radio Interview, KNUS-Denver, Apr. 20 1982, tr6851a
    - McNaught, Sep. 12, tr6852a
    - Briggs, Philip and Sidney Brown, Herb Stone, tr6853a
    - CPA Convention - Chicago, tr6854a
    - "Defamation," narrated by Harvey Fierstein for the Gay and Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation, tr6855a
    - "Defamation" (cont.), tr6856a
    - Dan Fiskin, tr6857a
    - Russell Frank, Paul Zappini, [?], Runaways, tr6858a
    - Russel Frank cont./SR Barbara/Scanlon "Bridge", tr6859a
    - Lou Gordon - Brian McNaught, Aug. 24 1974, tr6860a
    - McNeill Interview, WDET, tr6861a
    - McNeill Lecture, Nov. 20, and Questions and Answers, tr6862a
    - Carolyn Ray, Nov. 14 1980, tr6863a
    - Congressman Gerry E. Studds, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champagne, May 4 1986, tr6864a
    - Ron Wesner and Dick York interview for WITNESS, Sep. 21, tr6865a
    - R. Woxniak/McGrail/Human Services panel, May 23 1983, tr6866a
    - Artists, Gay and Lesbian - Introductions - Tape 1: Overview, tr6867a
    - Artists, Gay and Lesbian - Tape 2: Morning Session, tr6868a
    - Artists, Gay and Lesbian - Tape 3: Providers, tr6869a
    - Artists, Gay and Lesbian - Tape 4, tr6870a
    - Boston Project I and II, Police Lt. McNells - Debriefing, Discussion, tr6871a
    - Boston Project III, Steven Tierney/IV, Joseph D'Onofrio, tr6872a
    - Gay/Lesbian Disabled Citizens and City Services I and II, tr6873a
    - Gay/Lesbian Disabled Citizens and City Services III, tr6874a
    - Gay/Lesbian Elderly and City Services I and II, tr6875a
    - Gay/Lesbian Elderly and City Services III, tr6876a
    - Education and Information about Lesbians Roundtable - the B[?] Project, tr6877a
    - Education and Information about Lesbians Roundtable - the B[?] Project (cont.), tr6878a
    - Women's Roundtable/guests Brian McNaught, Fr. Kenneth Baker, Sister Jeannina Gramick, tr6879a
    - Lou Gordon program: "Are Homosexuals Going to Hell?", tr6880a
    - Health and Hospitals Roundtable - Tape I, tr6881a
    - Health and Hospitals Roundtable - Tape II, tr6882a
    - Health and Hospitals Roundtable - Tape III, tr6883a
    - Health and Hospitals Roundtable - Tape IV, tr6884a
    - Health and Hospitals Roundtable - Tape V, tr6885a
    - Lesbian Health Issue Roundtable Panel - Tape 1, tr6886a
    - Lesbian Health Issue Roundtable Panel - Tape 2, tr6887a
    - Boston Project - Press Confab, Mar. 4 1983, tr6888a
    - Stupek Show Aug. 15 1974 I and II, tr6889a
    - Stupek Show and McNaught WDET Aug. 1 1974, tr6890a
    - Stupek Show Aug. 15 1974 IV and V, tr6891a
    - Thornfield 1980 Tape 1, tr6892a
    - Thornfield 1980 Tape 2, tr6893a
    - Thornfield 1982 Winter Tape, tr6894a
    - Gay and Lesbian Minorities Roundtable I - Introduction: Overview/discussion/homophobia/racism, tr6895a
    - Gay and Lesbian Minorities Roundtable II - Relational legitimacy/immigration, tr6896a
    - Gay and Lesbian Minorities Roundtable III - Discussion/recommendations, tr6897a
    - Gay and Lesbian Minorities Roundtable IV - Wrap-up, tr6898a
    - Neighborhood Hearings Area I Mon. nite July 25, tr6899a
    - Neighborhood Hearings Area I Mon. nite July 25, tr6900a
    - Neighborhoods, tr6901a
    - Neighborhoods, tr6902a
    - Neighborhoods, tr6903a
    - Neighborhoods, tr6904a
    - Education Roundtable Opening, tr6905a
    - Education Roundtable Morning Discussion, tr6906a
    - Police Panel: Goldsmith, Gottschalk and Barry I: G/L as Victims of Violence, tr6907a
    - Police Panel: Victims of Violence - J.B., tr6908a
    - Police Panel III Tape One - Chuck Wexler/Charles Maplethorpe, tr6909a
    - Police/Community Relations II - Barry, Johnston, Vaiciulus, tr6910a
    - Police Safety/Legal Panels G/L Roundtable - Tape 4, tr6911a
    - Police and Safety/Legal Tape #2, tr6912a
    - Police panel 5 - Richard Iandali, tr6913a
    - Prison - Introductions, tr6914a
    - Prison - Introductions continued, tr6915a
    - Prison - After-Introductions - Specific issue brainstorming - I, tr6916a
    - Prison roundtable - Resource Development Panel, tr6917a
    - Prison - Education #2, tr6918a
    - [Prison?] 2 pm to 3/to other cassette, tr6919a
    - [Prison?] 3:30 start after technical interruption, tr6920a
    - Spanish Lesson Jan. 10, Nov. 20, tr6921a
    - Aug. 29 1980, tr6922a
    - I Youth Hearings: Gen. Dev. Overview: Ron Wozniak, SJ/SR Barbara [?]/Alan Tweedy - Adoption/Ed Roche, tr6923a
    - II Youth panel May 24, Human Services 4. Group Proc and Project Aware, tr6924a
    - II Youth Panel Human Services "Spec. Threats" - 1. George Smith May 24 1983, GAA/Ken Smith/G/L Hotline 5. May 24, tr6925a
    - II Youth Panel Human Services 2. Paul Robinson - BCH/Kevin Cranston 5-24 6., tr6926a
    - II Youth Panel Human Services 3. Ellen Haper-M.L. of Comm. Health Cmrs., tr6927a
    - No title [religion?], tr6928a
    - Thornfield 1989, Brian, 1989; tr6990a
    - Brian McNaught - Lou Gordon Program 1974, tr6991a
    - "HR NewsScan, Sept. 2000", Cassette audiotape (Box 22)
    - "My Brother Dan" by Bishop Gumbleton, Cassette audiotape (Box 22)
    - "McNaught Family, for Brian", CD (Box 22)
    - "Sex and Spirituality," WPM, December 2005; Cassette audiotape (Box 22)
  - Video Recordings
    - Brian McNaught, V179 (Box 25)
    - Brian McNaught, June 21, 1990; V180 (Box 25)
    - Brian, V181 (Box 25)
    - Brian McNaught, V182 (Box 25)
    - Gay Issues in the Workplace - McNaught, V183 (Box 25)
    - Growing Up Gay - McNaught, V184 (Box 25)
    - Homophobia in the Workplace - McNaught, V185 (Box 25)
    - On Being Gay - McNaught, V186 (Box 25)
    - To the Point, June 24, 1979; V187, use copy DVD-555 (Box 25)
    - RSVP Cruises '92, V190 (Box 25)
    - "Gay and Lesbian People in the Workplace: What are the Issues?" by Brian McNaught, VHS videotape (Box 22)
    - Signing of the Massachusetts Gay Rights Bill by Gov. Dukakis, November 15, 1989; VHS videotape (Box 22)
    - "Being Gay at Work" by Brian McNaught, VHS videotape (Box 22)
    - "Real Personal", September 13, 1995; VHS videotape (Box 22)
    - LEAGUE Conference: Pat Russo and Brian McNaught, 1994; VHS videotape (Box 22)
    - Gay and Straight: Our Common Ground. Presentation to Goldman Sachs, September 2003; VHS (Box 22)
    - Presentation to Morgan Stanley, September 2005; VHS (Box 22)
    - Presentation to New Ways Ministry Conference, February 2000; VHS (Box 22)
    - "Brian McNaught, 2004" DVD of Brian's youth prepared for his 60th birthday by his brother Tom, DVD (Box 22)
SEPARATED MATERIALS
Publications Removed From Collection 7590 - To Be Cataloged As Individual Books And Serials In The Human Sexuality Collection:
McNaught, Brian. On Being Gay: Thoughts on Family, Faith and Love, New York, St. Martin's Press, 1988 (dust jacket)
McNaught, Brian. On Being Gay: Thoughts on Family, Faith and Love, New York, St. Martin's Press, 1988 (paperback)
McNaught, Brian. Gay Issues in the Workplace, New York, St. Martin's Press, 1993 (dust jacket)
McNaught, Brian. A Disturbed Peace: Selected Writings of An Irish Catholic Homosexual, Washington, D.C., Dignity, Inc., 1981 (paperback)
McNaught, Brian. Which Side Are We On? Christian Commitment for the '80s, Oakland, Inter-Religious Task Force for Social Analysis, 1979 (paperback)
A Bodybuilding Course (David Carter) Stallion Enterprises
Adolescent Sexuality, Fall/Winter 1974(Vol.3 No.3)
America Living With AIDS (Report on the National Commission on Acquired, 1991
Immune Deficiency Syndrome) Aware, January 1975(Vol.1 No.2)
Campaign, 1978(No.26,No.3 2)
Capitol Hill (The Newsletter of the Gay Rights National Lobby), (Vol.1 No.3)
Christianity and Crisis, May 30/June l3, 1977(Vol.37 No.9/10)
Clinical Child Psychology, Summer 1980(Vol.9 No.2)
Dignity International, September/ October 1979
Dignity National Newsletter, February 1979(Vol.10 No.2)
Empathy, 1990/91(Vol. 2. No.2)
Fight the Right Action Kit (NGLTF), 1993
Gay Literature, Winter 1976(No. 5)
Gay News, April 26, 1984(No. 18)
Gays in Library Land, 1990
Gays on the Hill, No v/ Dec 1978(Vol.3. No.2)
Growing Up Gay: A Youth Liberation Pamphlet, September 1976
Homosexuality and Social Justice (Report of the Task Force on Gay/Lesbian Issues), July 1982
Integrity Forum. (Gay Episcopalians), 1979(Vol.5, No.2, Vol.6 No.l)
Journal is Current Social Issues, Spring 1978(Vol.15. No.l)
Keeping Posted, November 1986(Vol.23 No.2)
M2M: The New Catalog for Men, Fall 1994
Mandate, July 1976, July 1987(Vol2 No.15, Vol. 13 No.7)
More Light (Presbyterian), May/June 1979(No.36)
National Directory of Facilities and Services for Lesbian and Gay Alcoholics (The National Association of Lesbian and Gay Alcoholism Professionals), 1987
National Institute of Mental Health Task Force on Homosexuality: Final Report and Background Papers, 1972
New England Community Guide for Gays and Lesbians, 1982, 1983
New Zealand Gay News, Sept/Oct 1976(No. 9)
One in 10 (A profile of Alaska's Lesbian & Gay Community), 1986
POZ, April/May 1994(Vol.1 No.l)
Report on the Commission on Personal Privacy (Regular and Executive Summary), December 1982
RFD, Fall 1976(No. 9)
SEICUS, July 1978(Vol.6 No.6)
Shocking Gray, 1992
The Gay Coloring Book Queerball Products, 1980
The Humanist, March/ April 1978(Vol.28 No.2)
The Washington Monthly, December 1970(Vol.2 No.10)
Wilde Side: New England's Gay Guide, September 1, 1976(Vol.1, No.7)
Fag Rag, Winter 1975(No.11)
Gay News, December 3, 1976, September 4-11, 1981(Vol.1 No.2, Vol 5 No. 23)
Gay Life (Midwest Gay Newsleader), June 2, 1978(Vol 3 No. 38)
Gazette, Aug27-Sept2, 1981
GPU News, January 1979, August 1979(Vol. 8 No. 4, Vol 8 No. 11)
The Guide to Gay New England, March 15 to April 4
Hit Parade, 1978
Long Beach Gays, March 1981
Metro Gay News, April 1978(Vol.3, No.4)
Gay Philadelphia News, November 1977, April 15, 1978, May 1978, July 1978, August 15, 1978, September 1978, Oct 1978, February 1979, February 15, 1978(Vol 2 No. 2, Vol 2 No. 8, vol 2 No 10, Vol. 2 No 12, Vol. 3 No. 1, Vol 3 No 5)
National NOW Times (National Organization for Women), March 1982(Vol 15, No. 2)
Playguy, 1976(Vol 1 No.3)
Playgirl, (Vol 1)
Trader Dick and Friends Pull Out, August 13, 1975
The Blade (Washington DC), April 1976 November 1977 April 1978(Vol 7 No. 4 Vol 8 No. 11 Vol. 9 No. 4)
The Body Politic, February 1978
The Boston Phoenix, March 28, 1978
Contact (Gay Newspaper and Guide), December 25, 1974 Feb 5, 1975 March 19, 1975 (Issue 8-10)
Esplande, Sept 11, 1976 Sept 15, 1976 Sept 22, 1976 Sept 29, 1976 October 6, 1976 Oct 13, 1976 Oct 20, 1976 Sept 23, 1977